isina Abadi

■ alisina.abadi@mail.utoronto.ca | 💣 aliabadi1.github.io | 🖸 Aliabadi1 | 🛅 ali-abadi1

Summary_

Third year computer science specialist student studying at the University Of Toronto. Highly motivated, collaborative and enthusiastic. Aiming to utilize my skills in software development, web development and algorithms to add value to your company.

Education

University of Toronto

HONOURS BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE SPECIALIST AND MATHEMATICS MINOR

Sept. 2019 - Current

- UofT Deans List of Scholars (2019-2020, 2020-2021)
- UofT MCSS Honour Roll(2019-2020)

Work Experience

Kidney Health Education Research Group

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

August. 2021 - Current • In charge of creating new front and back end applications with PHP and Javscript to effectively display findings of the Kidney Health Education

- Research Group to over 20 thousand patients · Developing the Paper Writing Portal which is a document writing web application that allows researchers to write abstracts/publications with
- access to built in tools that help them query database for medical files and other references Responsible for managing security across our many websites to prevent vulnerabilities being exploited by instilling new security measures

University of Toronto

COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHING ASSISTANT

August, 2021 - Current

- Teaching Assistant for CSC236 (Intro to Theory of Computation)
- Prepared and conducted tutorials for classes of 40+ students to elicit and build upon knowledge from their lectures
- Responsible for grading tests and assignments for course sizes of 550+ students

Projects

Show Recommendation Generator Web Application

JAVASCRIPT (REACTJS), PYTHON (DJANGO), SQLITE, HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, GIT

- · Created a responsive web application using a ReactJS front end and Django back end to create show recommendations from shows the user already enjoyed
- · Utilized the Python Beautiful Soup library to scrap internet for 1000's of shows to potentially recommend to user and stored the data using SQL ite
- Communicated between database and frontend by using Django REST library

xModem File Transfer Server

- Utilized C to create a file transfer server between different computers both using the xModem file transfer protocol
- · Directly transferred bytes between computers by opening sockets on both ends without blocking to simultaneously be able to transfer data from other computers
- · Verified content of file transfer by using the CRC16 algorithm

Huffman Tree Compression/Decompression Application

PYTHON

- Leveraged Python to develop a file compression application by applying the Huffman lossless data compression algorithm
- Employed recursive binary tree algorithms on Huffman tree data to compress and decompress a variety of files(JPG, MP3, WAV, txt, BMP etc.)

Transit System Application

JAVA

- · Developed a mock transit system application with a group using java that mimicked the functionality of a real transit app whilst using proper design patterns(MVC, Oberserver, Factory) where most applicable
- · Utilized agile methodology and applied scrum process to efficiently organize and complete our work

Skills.

Languages: Python, C, Java, Javascript, PHP, Assembly, Racket, Haskell, HTML, CSS,

Frameworks: ReactJS, Vue.js, Django, React Native

Databases: MySQL, SQLite Version Control: Git